<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Macbook Pro on Timur Coding Stuff</title>
    <link>https://timurvafin.blog/tags/macbook-pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macbook Pro on Timur Coding Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:42:25 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://timurvafin.blog/tags/macbook-pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ollama set up and my use cases</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/ollama_use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:42:25 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/ollama_use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After successfully installing Ventura on my old Mac (see previous post), I went straight to installing Llama and trying out models. I used the following YouTube tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GWB9ApTPTv4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GWB9ApTPTv4&lt;/a&gt;, which I found to be really good. The Llama documentation is also great: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ollama/ollama/blob/main/README.md&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ollama/ollama/blob/main/README.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have tried running Llama 3.2 7B and CodeGemma 7B. After getting used to Chat GPT, this seems like a significant slowdown. However, given that I have specific use cases in mind, it might still be suitable for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading OS on my MacbookPro Mid-2012</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/upgadingmac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:40:26 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/upgadingmac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love my MacBook Pro mid-2012; it served me well until I bought the one with the M1 chip. I waited for a long time to upgrade because each new line of MacBooks seemed somehow worth it. However, I was really frustrated when Apple decided to solder RAM and then removed the ports, which eventually reached an absolute low point when they introduced the useless Touch Bar, removed USB-A and HDMI ports, had problems with the display cable, and featured an awful keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
