<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Task Manager on Timur Coding Stuff</title>
    <link>https://timurvafin.blog/tags/task-manager/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Task Manager on Timur Coding Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:23:04 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://timurvafin.blog/tags/task-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Task managers</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/taskmanagers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:23:04 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/taskmanagers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to set up tasks for the week, month, or year, and it really helps to offload thoughts and be more productive. Unfortunately, I am not always consistent about it. And I wish for a system that would help with it. This led me to try multiple different apps, and now I have a long love-hate relationship with task managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-an-ideal-task-manager-look-like-for-me&#34;&gt;What an ideal task manager look like for me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progress - many task managers make the task disappear once it&amp;rsquo;s done! It doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring any joy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple buckets for different tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics! I do love numbers and would like to see my capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-platform - has a mobile app or is at least adjusted for mobile screens, but has full functionality on desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not too complicated; it should be easy to add tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals - group tasks for certain goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*Telegram support - I can just message to add a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up using Microsoft OneNote as it&amp;rsquo;s multi-platform and allows me to add stuff quickly. I like that I can see the tasks, and when I plan for the next week, I can just copy-paste from the previous one. And because it&amp;rsquo;s free-format, it allows fine-tuning as needed. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any analytics, and when I set up a system for a week, I have to double-check to see how my weekly tasks align with monthly or yearly goals. Also, at the beginning of the week, I might have one plan, but sometimes the week requires adjustments, and I end up adding more tasks later in the week. It&amp;rsquo;s alright, but the problem is that my original tasks are still there and create a sense of stagnation. Therefore, I don&amp;rsquo;t understand - should I plan better? How much should I reserve for additional tasks? And what&amp;rsquo;s even achievable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
