<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Timur Coding Stuff</title>
    <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Timur Coding Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:42:25 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://timurvafin.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ollama set up and my use cases</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/ollama_use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:42:25 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/ollama_use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I successfully installed Ventura to my old mac (see previous post) I went straight to installing Ollama and trying models.
I have used following youtube tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GWB9ApTPTv4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GWB9ApTPTv4&lt;/a&gt; and I can say it is really good. And Ollama documentation is great as well: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ollama/ollama/blob/main/README.md&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ollama/ollama/blob/main/README.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I tried running llama 3.2 7b and codegemma 7b. After getting used to chat gpt this seems like crazy slow. But, given that I have specific usecases in mind that might still fit me well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading OS on my MacbookPro Mid-2012</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/upgadingmac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:40:26 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/upgadingmac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love my MacBook Pro mid-2012. It served me well until I bought the one with M1 chip. I waited for a long time to updgrade because each new line of the macbooks seemed to be worth somehow. I was really frustrated when Apple decided to solder RAM and then removed the ports until it reached an absolutely trash when they introduced useless touchbar, removed usb-a and hdmi ports, had problems with display cable and an awful keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to My Blog: A Place for Code and Projects</title>
      <link>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 11:15:49 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timurvafin.blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I’ve decided to create this space as a personal knowledge base where I can store useful code snippets, document my projects, and track their evolution over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-this-blog&#34;&gt;Why This Blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I often revisit past code, whether it’s a quick Python script, a Vue.js component, or a backend API. Instead of digging through old repositories or scattered notes, I wanted a structured way to keep track of useful solutions and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
